# Dan Hough

Full-stack mobile and web developer



#### About Dan

I'm a London-based freelance software engineer. I spend a lot of my time working on web applications, native iOS Applications and NodeJS applications. I am comfortable going up and down the stack in order to implement a new feature or develop a product. I have more than 4 years developing software professionally, and I am keen to learn more and extend my skills in programming as well as product management.

## Lists of Things

**Hobbies**: Bouldering, Squash, Snowboarding, Running. Illlustration & drawing, design. Singing, guitar & songwriting. Music. Public speaking. Cinema, television, coffee, general Internetting.

**Recent Books:** Joel on Software by Joel Spolsky, JavaScript: The Good Parts by Douglas Crockford, 007: Moonraker by Ian Fleming, American Gods by Neil Gaiman, The Aquariams of Pyongyang by Kang Chol-Hwan

#### Side Projects & Cool Stuff I've Made:

Interfake(https://github.com/basicallydan/interfake) StreetScout (http://streetscoutapp.com) SkiFree.js (https://basicallydan.github.io/skifree.js) Busking (http://youtu.be/LmDXpLbi2w0)

Windows or Mac? Happy with both.

# Recent Employment History

## **Upmysport**

Contract Mobile Developer, February 2014 - Present

Greenfield project. Single-Page BackboneJS app for Cordova/PhoneGap to work on iOS and Android, utilising existing REST API. Push notifications, FB login.

## Gojimo

Contract Backend Developer, November 2013 - January 2014
Refactoring and extending a large NodeJS
(express-based) REST API. Worked with a team of mobile devs, and integrating AWS for asset management.

#### Huddle

Junior Developer to Developer, July 2011 - November 2013

Worked on a backend REST API (.NET), frontend single-page web app using **Knockout.js**, with 1000+ daily users. Legacy system refactoring into a **scalable SOA** system. Led a skunkworks team. Joined mobile team to work on native iOS apps. Agile methodology: **SCRUM** teams, daily **standups**, estimations, elaborations & retrospectives.

# Formal Education & Training

# The University of Sheffield

September 2006 - June 2010

1st Class BEng Software Engineering

# **Technical Skills**

Experience	
<sub>Meh</sub> JavaScript	Hero
Node.js	
Objective-C	
PHP	
C#	
Recency	
Never JavaScript	This week
Node.js	
Objective-C	
PHP	
C#	

#### Other Programming Languages & Technologies

Backbone, Handlebars, Gulp, Java, Python, PHP, MongoDB, SQL, CSS, SASS, LESS, (X)HTML (inc. HTML5), Rake, Grunt, XML, Pascal, Haskell, PROLOG.

#### Software

Sublime Text, Git, Visual Studio, XCode, Adobe Photoshop, Flash & Illustrator (CS1-CS5), Mac OS X, MS Windows (ME - 7), Linux (openSuSE and Ubuntu), SVN, Eclipse.

#### **Software Engineering Concepts**

Agile Methodologies, Object-oriented Design, REST, Test-Driven Design, Continuous Integration, Behaviour-Driven Design, Coincidence-Driven Design, SOA, MVC, MVVM, AJAX, Modular Design, Event-driven programming.

In this Curriculum Vitae I have attempted to include only the most relevant information for readability and brevity. However, if you have any further questions about my experience or skills please feel free to email me at daniel.hough@gmail.com or see my personal website danhough.com:)